Guide to the Spy Hop Productions independent film collection 2000-2009
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 18)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Medium shot of people practicing tai chi with Pioneer Park sign in foreground
    Medium shot of a woman practicing tai chi
    Protesters in Pioneer Park hold a banner which reads "The world needs truthfulness, compassion, tolerance"
    Protesters in Pioneer Park hold a banner which reads "Faulin Dafa"
    St. Provo Brewery billboard which reads "If you just said 'O My Heck!' it's probably not for you"
    A homeless man sits on the sidewalk with a multi-lingual sign asking for beer money
    Abortion protestors stand out side of an abortion clinic (?) with signs which read "Save the Babies" and "The Killing Place"
    Interview with a woman (Jo Scott) working as an abortion protestor who is protesting Salt Lake Olympic Committee (SLOC)s distribution of condoms which her group views as Salt Lake Olympic Committee (SLOC) condoning "explicit sex". Woman tells interviewer that her group was on CNN the night before as they thought they were in the PETA parade but accidentally ended up in the torch parade.
    Interview with a man (Mr. Scott) working as an abortion protestor who tells about his frustration concerning Park City protesting ordinances which only allow signs to be a certain size. Mr. Scott argues that this ordinance was only enforced on those protesting abortion due to the graphic nature of their posters.
    Beyond this point, tape appears to be corrupted and is unplayable
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 19)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Back of man and woman in blue and white Olympic parkas as they walk from camera (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Back of man in a blue and white Olympic parka as he walks from camera (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Zoom out on Coca-Cola logo of the Coke Torch relay mini van (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Olympic Torch relay in Salt Lake City, torch passed to runner #076 (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Footage of people cheering the relay runner and entourage (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Hand off to next torch runner from #076 who is greeted by friends and family (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Japanese drum group performs on one of the cultural event stages (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Japanese drum group performs, pan across crowd and vendors and back to stage again (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Pan across collage of Japanese-Americans in photographs dating mostly from the 1930s (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Two little girls stand in front of a table displaying origami items (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young man in a yellow UTA sleeveless parka (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Footage of the young man leaving the interview area and continuing to speak to cameraman and/or interviewer on the grounds of the Salt Lake City and County Building (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Young man and camera crew approach a group of four young women and carry on a conversation with them (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a man in a black jacket (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a boy (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a man in a blue jacket (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young woman in a white and black jacket (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young woman in a light blue turtleneck sweater (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with Brandon Clift, Adel Jones, and Jace Everett (?). After the introduction point in the interview sound is corrupted. (sound corrupted, only partial sound)
    Rap group performance. Brandon Clift from above interview raps with two other young men. Sound is corrupted shortly after the group begins performing. (sound corrupted, only partial sound)
    Interview with a young boy in a gray pullover. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Chinese percussion band performance on a stage with a Chinese dragon dances.
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 20)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Man holding a sign which reads "Corporate Games Corporate Corruption"
    People on the side of the road protesting the Olympic Rodeo as a form of animal cruelty. Signs read "The Olympic Rodeo is Cruelty for a Buck", "Teach Our Children Compassion", "Keep Cruel Rodeo Out of the Olympics" and "Don't Shame the Games". Some protesters dressed as cows and horses.
    Interview with two rodeo protestors. Sound cuts in and out. (sound corrupted, only partial sound)
    Young man in a white parka walks by the camera and upon seeing it, walks back and begins rapping into the lens. (sound corrupted, only partial sound)
    Stakes with signs which read "Peace in Mexico" for example for countries all over the world, each sign written in the language of that country.
    Stakes in the ground which read "May Peace Prevail on Earth"
    Shot of a Visitor Information tent
    Shot of a First Aid tent
    Shots of wooden snow shoes and snow sleds
    Shots of children and families walking around an area with Native American tepees, the Budweiser wagon, Budweiser event tent, volunteers, a Utah pioneer wagon, bales of hay, and frontiersman tents. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Native American band plays on a large stage in front of the Salt Lake City and County Building. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Inside of an Olympic paraphernalia store tent (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Women and children outside in line at a concession stand (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Women and children pose for a picture (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Shot of Olympic volunteers in yellow parkas (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Long shot of Native American band plays on a large stage in front of the Salt Lake City and County Building in the background. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Two people sitting on separate benches swing their feet. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    A volunteer at Information Services assists a man. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Two women, volunteers and Information Services wearing uniform parkas laugh as they walk down a street. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    A man in a red parka collects trash on the grounds of the Salt Lake City and County Building. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Long shot facing west of 400 South, at 500 (?) West. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Shot of a UTA bus with a wrap on it of a pair of figure skaters. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Various shots of 300 South near the Broadway Theater. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Yellow parka clad volunteers walk down a sidewalk in downtown Salt Lake City. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Temporary, event fencing with signs which read "World Party Bud (Budweiser) Gallivan Center". (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Olympic Torch map. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Various shots of people walking around downtown. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    People milling around Ticket booth. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Olympic pin seller/trader set up with a table, corkboards, and easels on a street. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Anti-Mormon protesters and hold signs which read "Mormon Jesus is Devil's Brother" and "Joseph Smith was a False Prophet". (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Long shot of LDS Salt Lake Temple. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Slalom photo in window of ZCMI Center (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Medium shot of Salt Palace (sound corrupted, no sound)
    American Red Cross volunteers chat around a parked ambulance (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Shot of trax trolley, picture of a snowboarder in background as a horse and buggy drive by. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Shot of the Festival Art Gallery as people walk by. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Person dressed as an Idaho potato waves to passersby. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Extreme long/panoramic shot of Salt Lake City, possibly taken from Ensign Peak. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    USA Olympic Flag blowing in wind. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Various shots of Olympic flags, pedestrians.
    Vendor selling rhinestone jewelry (USA flag pins, USA flag rings) Utah magnets and Olympic shirts, hats and other paraphernalia.
    Interview with a young woman in a blue and black parka. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with two teen girls. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a man in a tan parka. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young woman in a black, fur-trimmed parka. (sound corrupted, no sound)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 21)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Various shots of a crowd milling around in a park (Free Speech Zone?).
    Some of the people in the crowd hold signs. One sign for the Kensington Welfare Rights Union reads "Everyone has the right to living wage jobs, Article 23." (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a woman in a wool pea coat with the Kensington Welfare Rights Union. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Shot of sign which reads "Right to Communicate, Deaf Pride". (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with policemen watching the crowd in the "Free Speech Zone" (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Blonde woman with the Kensington Welfare Rights Union sings in front of a poster with a picture and quote ("Poverty is but the worst form of violence") by Mahatma Gandhi. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Woman in wool pea coat introduces another woman wearing a baseball cap and a blue wool poncho. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    One sign reads "Re-Organize our rights to life," another reads "Green Games Sell Out". (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Woman for the Kensington Welfare Rights Union in a wool pea coat sings (?) as another woman interprets in American Sign Language. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A woman in a brown plaid coat with a green scarf speaks after she is introduced by the woman for the Kensington Welfare Rights Union in a wool pea coat. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Various shots of a crowd milling around in a park (Free Speech Zone?). (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Man in red parka speaks after he is introduced by the woman for the Kensington Welfare Rights Union in a wool pea coat. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Man in red parka with a green scarf, signs in American Sign Language after he is introduced by the woman for the Kensington Welfare Rights Union in a wool pea coat. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Man in black leather jacket and a knit cap and a man in a brown plaid coat speak after they are introduced by the woman for the Kensington Welfare Rights Union in a wool pea coat. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Woman in a brown trench coat and a red scarf speaks after she is introduced by the woman for the Kensington Welfare Rights Union in a wool pea coat. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Woman in a grey coat and a lime green fleece scarf and a woman in a dark jacket and green scarf with a yellow knit cap speak after they are introduced by the woman for the Kensington Welfare Rights Union in a wool pea coat. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Crowd marches and holds a sign which reads "March for our lives: Poor People's Economic Human Rights Campaign" in park (Free Speech Zone?). (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Volunteer police in yellow parkas run to park (Free Speech Zone?). (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Volunteer police speak to people holding sign which reads "March for our lives: Poor People's Economic Human Rights Campaign". (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A dozen police vehicles with their lights on escort two black vehicles with waving flags as they drive down street near park. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Protestors parade down the street holding their signs with police escort. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a woman in a car with one man and two other women as they wait for the protestors to pass so they can drive on. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A man in a grey suit speaks to a police officer in a yellow parka. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Protestors parade down the street next to President's Circle at the University of Utah as they hold their signs. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Woman in a wool pea coat with the Kensington Welfare Rights Union speaks on the lawn of President's Circle. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Women holding a sign for the Kensington Welfare Rights Union attempt to keep marching but when they reach the police barricade are stopped by officers. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Officer assists a man in zip-tie handcuffs into the back of a police van as the crowd watches. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a man in a dark jacket and a knit cap. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A two man band performs on stage -- one on guitar the other playing a diggery do(?). (Sound corrupted, no sound)
    Night, outside of Rice Eccles Stadium (Caldron Park), people walk by and a fire engine with its lights on is parked beside the stadium.
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 22)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Three young men on a stage rap, including improvisational rapping from suggestions shouted out by the audience. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Shot of a crowd waving small US flags as Katie Couric and another announcer discuss the Olympiads on parade during the opening ceremonies. (Voice of Couric and other announcer appears to be from a large monitor which the crowd is watching, off screen)
    Shot of the off screen monitor broadcasting the opening ceremonies parade.
    Shots of various sculptures outside of the Salt Lake City and County Building.
    Shot of a wooden stake with the words "May peace be in New Zealand" written upon it.
    Shot of a wooden stake with the words "May peace be in Fiji" written upon it.
    Shot of a wooden stake with the words "May peace be in Australia" written upon it.
    Sculpture of a Native American outside of the Salt Lake City and County Building.
    Shot of a crowd watching monitor displaying the opening ceremonies from the grounds of the Salt Lake City and County Building. (Voice of Couric and other announcer appears to be from a large monitor which the crowd is watching, off screen)
    Interview with a young boy. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Shot of Olympic banner on the Medals Plaza stage (?)
    Cheerleading dancers perform on Medals Plaza stage. Camera pans across the crowd and back to stage.
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 23)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Beach Boys perform on Medals Plaza stage (?)
    Various shot of crowd on the grounds of the Salt Lake City and County Building as the Beech Boys perform in the background.
    Shot of a woman in a US Flag coat with flags from countries all over the world sticking out of her hat.
    Interview with dancers from Cyprus High School in Magna, Utah performing at the Olympics.
    Various shots of food vendor tables inside of an event tent.
    Interview with a woman working at a food vendor table as she explains what each item is (i.e. Japanese rice balls).
    Shots of the stage decorations and lights in the same event tent, Chinese flag and drum.
    Interview with a woman, JoAnn Wong, with the Utah Chinese Community on February 12, 2002. Wong explains that in that event tent they are celebrating Chinese New Year, year of the horse.
    Various shots of horse art.
    Downtown Festival grounds at the Salt Lake City and County building.
    Shots of the "Wild West" display at the Downtown Festival grounds.
    Shots of a man selling and making foam figurine carvings. Interview with him translated from Chinese to English.
    A person dressed in a panda suit greets people.
    A woman on the Medals Plaza stage performs Indian dances.
    Interview with a man, Pradeep (Phillip) Mehta, in the crowd at the Medals Plaza from India working for the Salt Lake City Corp Olympic Plan. Phillip is asked about his role in the Olympic planning and support.
    Folk band performs on Medals Plaza stage.
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 24)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Various shots of downtown from a moving vehicle:
    "Welcome to Salt Lake City" Budweiser sign
    Antique store
    Salt Lake City and County Building in background as vehicle drives east on 300 South (?)
    Maverick Gas Station
    "A Semester to Remember: Stay on track with transit" sign at the University of Utah
    "Are you in the dark...about where to park? Don't cry and wail...just take light rail" sign at the University of Utah
    Field house with Rice Eccles Stadium in the background at the University of Utah
    University of Utah Bookstore
    Global Justice flier at the University of Utah
    "Freedom of speech at the Olympics?" flier at the University of Utah
    "The Games are comin'...get the spirit...U Winterfest 2002" sign at the University of Utah
    Red Olympic banner flags out side of the Marriot library at the University of Utah
    "South Campus Drive Closed" and "Detour" signs at the University of Utah
    Approximately twenty blue Olympic banner flags outside of Rice Eccles Stadium at the University of Utah
    "Road Closed Ahead" sign at the University of Utah
    Budweiser billboards with the Shilo hotel in the background, downtown Salt Lake City
    Budweiser World Party at the Galivan Center logo, zoom out to the billboard in front of the Shilo hotel
    Newspaper vending machine decorated with Olympics posters on Main Street, downtown Salt Lake
    Photo of a woman representing the curling event covering the Wells Fargo building then zoom out to see another one on the Marriot Hotel next to it of cross country skiers (building wrap)
    Coke vending machine with Salt Lake 2002 logo on it at the ZCMI Center
    Men in an event tent constructing large wooden boxes and painting them white, one has black dots on it to resemble a giant die (singular for dice)
    Salt Lake City and County Building grounds (Before the start of the Olympics?)
    Picnic tables on the Salt Lake City and County Building grounds
    Toilet and urinal, apparently broken and removed from the Salt Lake City and County Building and placed in a junk pile by a parking lot
    A man installs a toilet paper dispenser in a bathroom stall
    Shot of a sculpture of a Native American with the Salt Lake City and County Building in the background
    Man in an event tent constructing large wooden boxes and painting them white, one has black dots on it to resemble a giant die (singular for dice) listens to rock music and begins to strum his paint roller as if it were a guitar
    Men constructing the Medals Plaza stage at the Salt Lake City and County Building grounds
    People milling around on the Salt Lake City and County Building grounds
    Flags from different countries next to stakes which read "May peace be in New Zealand" for example
    Two men unrolling a large spool of portable walkway on the Salt Lake City and County Building grounds
    Men working in scaffolding on the Salt Lake City and County Building grounds
    Teens holding flags around the peace stakes on the Salt Lake City and County Building grounds
    Mayor Rocky Anderson cuts ribbon at the dedication for the Olympic pavilion on the Salt Lake City and County Building grounds
    Teens holding flags around the peace stakes shout out the country name in the dedication ceremony for the Olympic pavilion on the Salt Lake City and County Building grounds
    Footage taken from a vehicle on 500 South as vehicle passes the Little America hotel
    Footage of a truck with TVs on the sides showing rodeo cruelty with signs which read "Cruelty is not in the Olympic spirit"
    TV Coca-Cola billboard on a street
    Signs on the University of Utah campus which read "We're the host...the world's our guest...enjoy the games...let's show them our best" on which someone crossed out "enjoy" and wrote "fuck" in marker
    People wait in a hallway
    A young man talks on a cell phone
    A lounge with plush theater chairs against the wall in an event tent, room appears to be under construction in some areas. Art and murals are around the tent and it appears to be the "dice tent" seen earlier on the tape
    Black police sport utility vehicles (SUVs) parked outside of a building
    A man doing a sound check in front of a sheet of particle board painted black
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 25)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Various shots of US flags in Salt Lake City
    Coca-Cola banner
    Super Wash car wash bulletin board which reads "Shine like the torch"
    Olympic Torch Relay stands and stage set up in the parking lot of a Smiths grocery store in Tooele
    Goshute Native Americans perform on the Olympic Torch Relay stage set up in the parking lot of a Smiths grocery store in Tooele
    Chevrolet tent
    Chevrolet truck with the "Chevrolet: on the road to Salt Lake City, we'll be there"
    Olympic designed Police badge which reads "Tooele City, Senior Patrol, Kay Warburton, Utah, 2002, 2H94"
    Chevrolet semi and trailer
    Goshute Native American chief speaks to audience
    Goshute Native Americans dance on stage
    People holding flags of different nations
    Girl singing country on the Olympic Torch stage
    Unveiling of Coca-Cola's Olympic Art Competition winner's artwork and announcement
    Coca-Cola inspirational commercial shown from a monitor on a large trailer next to the Olympic Torch stage in Tooele
    Chevrolet spokeswoman, Erynna, presents Olympic pins to Tooele mayor as a thank you.
    Blonde young woman sings on stage
    Olympic Torch Relay spokesman addresses the audience and talks about the route for the torch and how the torchbearers were selected
    Man in a red parka and black cowboy hat (Coca-Cola spokesperson?) leads the crowd in a chant of USA
    Crowd waits for the torch to arrive, Payless Shoe Source store in the background
    Close up of the travel Olympic caldron
    Arrival of the torchbearer, Brett Bevin, who lit the travel Olympic caldron.
    Performance by Douglas Spottedeagle, who won the first Grammy by a Utah resident for Native American tribal music
    Shot of the travel Olympic caldron with Douglas Spottedeagle playing in the background
    Utah Highway Patrol Olympic logo on a Highway Patrol car
    Stop sign on which someone has placed a red bumper which reads "wearing fur"
    Japanese, Olympic, and Korean flags hanging from a building
    Mannequins dressed in Olympic gear and a sign in the foreground which reads "Official wears of Japanese Delegation, Salt Lake 2002"
    Yellow banner hanging in a window which reads "The hub of Asia: _____ Dynamic Korea"
    Interview with a man on the street. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Shot of Lamb's Grill Cafe, located in The Herald Building at 169 South Main Street, front window decorated with flags and Olympic parapenalia (sound corrupted, no sound)